In order to make it easier for users to create hair loss results, we launched the hair loss vinegar generator in the 2024.2 version.
By using this function, users can self-define and generate multiple hair loss results.
In addition, in order to improve usability, we also provided 15 hair loss predictions in the Connect business city, so that users can directly use them.
In this video, I will introduce the hair loss vinegar generator in detail and how to apply the hair loss that it wants to generate.
First, open the project file.
The hair loss prediction adjusted from the Connect or pre-adjusted by yourself will be dragged to the object window and applied on the board.
Select the hair loss material.
In the property editor, before opening the hair loss generator, the basic parameters such as hair material, hair type, and so on have been set.
Then pull the scroll down.
Find the default image.
Click on the hair loss next to the default image.
Open the window of the hair loss generator.
In the hair loss generator, there are two default images, the long-distance image and the curved-direction image.
You can adjust the long-distance image and the curved-direction image to easily generate hair loss.
Click on the long-distance image and the curved-direction image with the mouse to see the long-distance image and the curved-direction image.
On the left is the corresponding default preview effect,
and on the right is the adjustable attribute.
These parameters can be adjusted in any way,
and can be previewed on the left to check the default effect generated.
First, let's come to the length chart.
Under the attributes on the right of the length chart,
there are two attributes, including the cutting chart and the editing effect.
If these two attributes are not displayed on the menu,
you can click on the small triangle on the left.
Cutting chart and editing effect, these two attributes,
are used to set the length effect of hair vinegar.
First, let's look at the cutting chart.
The cutting chart is mainly used to show different lengths of hair in the same texture pattern.
It contains the mode, image level,
low area length and high area length four parameters.
Currently, the four parameters are gray.
To make it adjustable,
the cutting chart must be added here.
Next, let's explain each parameter separately.
To better understand and apply.
First is the mode.
It includes RGB and alpha modes.
Select RGB10.
The length of the hair depends on the grayness of the cutting chart.
The cutting chart needs to use gray.
Among them, the black area indicates the lowest hair length.
The white area indicates the highest hair length.
If you choose the alpha mode,
the length of the hair depends on the transparency of the cutting chart.
The cutting chart needs to apply transparency.
The transparent area indicates the lowest hair length.
The non-transparent area indicates the highest hair length.
Next, let's look at the image level.
It can adjust the intensity of gray.
Increasing the value can make the cut effect more obvious.
Next is the length of the low area and the length of the high area.
These two parameters can adjust the shortest and longest hair length.
Next, let's look at the editing effect.
The editing effect includes intensity and randomness.
Let's look at the intensity first.
The higher the intensity value,
the greater the difference in hair length from the edge to the center.
This creates a sharper hair hair.
The intensity below is random.
It can adjust whether the length of the hair on the entire surface of the fabric is consistent or irregular.
The higher the value, the more inconsistent the length of the hair hair.
And the long and short hair hair distribution is also irregular.
Next, let's look at the curve distribution.
Let's look at the curve direction chart.
It includes two properties, hair loss and hair loss details.
First, click on hair loss.
Hair loss makes the hair show the effect of one hair.
It contains intensity, hair loss density, random direction, intensity, and random four parameters.
Next, let's explain the meaning of each parameter separately.
To better understand and apply.
First is the intensity.
The property can adjust the intensity of the hair on each direction of the curve.
The higher the intensity, the more obvious the hair loss, the stronger the three-dimensional effect.
Next is the density of hair loss.
It can adjust the density of hair loss.
The higher the value, the higher the density of hair loss.
The smaller the hair loss, the closer it is.
The smaller the value, the lower the density of hair loss.
The larger the hair loss, the more scattered it is.
About random direction and random intensity.
These two parameters can set the curve direction of hair loss adjustment.
It is consistent or irregular.
Next, let's click on hair loss details.
Hair loss details are used to adjust the detail effect of each hair loss.
It contains five parameters.
The function meaning of the first four parameters is similar to what is said above.
There is no more explanation.
Finally, the intensity of hair loss is increased.
It can adjust the concentration of each hair loss.
At the same time, the direction of each hair loss remains unchanged.
The intensity of hair loss is higher.
It is correct for hair loss.
With the highest density setting, it can be made the hair loss smooth and loose.
It's like being tidied up.
Next, we will follow the meaning of the attributes parameters as described in the previous video.
Let's adjust this hair loss.
First, let's see how to adjust this hair loss effect based on the preview.
Open the length chart.
Because this hair loss effect does not need to show hair loss of different lengths.
So there is no need to use the cutting chart.
This hair is a bit sharp on each side, so adjust the strength a little bigger, 0.3 is fine.
You can pull the slider or enter the value directly.
The length of each hair is called the rule.
So it's good to have the value here within the 0.1 range, the value of 0.08 is fine.
After adjusting the length picture, come to the bend direction picture.
Let's look at the hair vinegar first.
The hair vinegar shows a certain three-dimensional effect, so adjust the strength value to the appropriate value of 0.45.
The density of the hair vinegar is not very dense, so adjust the density of the vinegar to 0.2.
The bending direction and bending strength of the hair vinegar are all called rules, so keep it at 0 or enter 0.05 here.
Next, let's look at the hair vinegar details.
The previous four parameters can be set according to the direction of the hair vinegar.
Let's look at the hair vinegar.
First, adjust the detail effect of the single hair vinegar to adjust.
According to the effect, adjust the value to the appropriate value.
Finally, the looseness.
Since the hair in the single hair vinegar is slightly open, so here the value is adjusted to 0.45.
After adjusting the properties of each parameter, be sure to click on the application first and then click on close.
The property settings made earlier will be applied to the hair.
Finally, open the synchronization rendering of the rendering window to see the final effect.
If there is no problem, output the rendering image.
Next, I will show you the final hair rendering image.
Next, let's see how to set this hair hair effect that presents a partial flower shape.
Open the hair vinegar generator.
Come to the cut image under the length image.
Add the pre-made black and white flower-shaped image.
Note that the cut image is a gray image.
For example, the mode should choose RGB mode.
After adding, the following properties can be adjusted according to the effect you want.
For example, I want to make the hair vinegar in the flower-shaped area more clear and obvious.
You can adjust the image level to the appropriate size.
For example, adjust to 0.65.
I want to have a certain length of hair in the low area.
You can adjust the height of the low area to the appropriate size.
Adjust it to 0.2.
After adjusting the properties, click on the application and close.
Open the rendering window and run the synchronization rendering.
Check the final effect.
After no problem, output the rendering image.
Next, I will show you the final hair hair rendering image designed with a partial flower shape.
We believe that the application of the new hair hair preset and hair vinegar generator by Kinect will improve your design experience and expand your creativity.
We look forward to your use of the hair hair vinegar generator to play with hair.
Thank you for watching.
See you next time.